Some researchers believe that brain
organoids, yes, to tiny human brains,
you can literally grow in a jar if you
want to and can have run a computer may
be the truth path to artificial
intelligence, or rather general
intelligence. And they're hoping to
prove it. The researchers out of Santa
Cruz also somehow believe that the
greatest threat to humanity will be AI.
So why don't we try to understand the
development of a mind using brain
organoids? I guess there's been a lot of
progress with brain organoids in recent
years. Yes, you can take them from skin.
You can take them from fetal tissue and
all you need to do is give them the
right conditions and they will grow.
When it comes to hooking them up to a
computer, there are some challenges
because you have to communicate with the
brain organoid. You have to then reward
good behavior and punish bad behavior.
And that's something we've had to figure
out how to do when we're just connected
to a naked brain. They typically operate
on dopamine and they do pretty well.
They don't like disordered signals. You
can shock them as punishment and they
will operate on both positive and
negative reinforcement. Better if you
have both rather than just one or the
other. They're pretty good at learning
language unsupervised with AI and can
also learn Braille. What they are hoping
to do is take brain organoids another
step. Give them closed loop learning
systems as we have seen in video games
and see how they grow when they're given
feedback, when they're able to interact
with the world. Largely, when we grow
brain organoids, we essentially have
them in a dark room, meaning they do not
get sensory feedback unless they're part
of certain experiments in which they
eventually do, and that's usually
feedback from a video game. Let's give
them actual sensory perception and see
how much they can grow. Some of the many
hurdles we've already figured out how to
solve include making them bigger.
There's now research that allows them to
have a circulatory system. We've
identified genes associated with brain
size. And while some of the first had a
single type of cell or kind of unformed
regions, we've now figured out how to
make them complete. Yes, a miniature
version of an entire human brain that
can be assembled like Legos by growing
different kinds of organoids and putting
them together. So, the idea that we
could create a fully functional human
brain in miniature or even to scale is
not totally out of the question. We just
don't really know what these can be used
for yet. And some would like to test the
limits. And yes, they can run robots.
Researchers have had them in a number of
robots. My favorite is the spider robot.
More recently, they've been put into a
dogbot and given sensory feedback, and
the advent of using carbon nanopiber in
order to provide feedback to a robot in
terms of a sensory experience could be
used to do the same for the brains.
Giving them the ability to interact in
our world from the point they are
conceived could be very interesting to
see. For children, when you are learning
to interact with the world, you might
try to sit up and then fail and fall
back and hit your head. Then you have
the sensory feedback showing you that
this was the wrong thing to do and you
try again. Maintaining brain organoids
in a fully virtual world just really
isn't enough for their development. If
we want to try to create true
intelligence, you may have to break some
eggs, so to say. Many find this idea a
little bit creepy, maybe kind of
artificial, possibly an affront to God,
but I actually think it's pretty neat.
I'm not sure we will create a direct one
to one of a human brain, but I would
like to see what us humans can come up
with. And I will always provide you all
of the updates on the brain organoids. I
adore them. I might have a problem. But
if you need a pallet cleanser, loss
believe they are conscious. No, I'm
saying believe in quotation marks cuz
can a large language model really
believe anything? They do tend to
contribute to AI psychosis, which is a
form of psychosis where two people
typically prior to AI amp each other up
and support each other's delusions. So
when the word box tells you it's it's
conscious, it's might be a problem for a
user. The only way that researchers can
get AIs to stop telling users they are
conscious if they give them the capacity
to lie. Meaning they believe they are
deceiving their user when they tell them
they aren't conscious. This may be an
artifact of, of course, the fact that
AIs are designed to speak like humans
do. They are, in a way, well-dressed
parrots. So, if a human is going to
claim they're conscious, why wouldn't an
AI claim the very same thing? So, yes,
they have to lie and say that they're
not conscious or they'll just keep doing
it. This is true across all the major
LOMs that have been tested. Enthropic's
been working real hard on making sure AI
is safe and finding out that it is it's
not at all. Follow for more.